<PAGE>
	<VAR match="VAR_ORIGIN" replace="" />
	<VAR match="VAR_CVSID" replace=""/>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_STARTED" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_BUILDING" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2-started.xml" />
	
	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

    	<h1>Building OpenConnect</h1>

<p>Unless you need to test the very latest version, you should not
need to build OpenConnect for yourself. Your operating system should
have a <a href="packages.html">prepackaged</a> version which you can
install; if it does not then file a bug or enhancement request asking for
one.</p>

<h2>Requirements</h2>
<p>To build OpenConnect from its source code, you will need the following
libraries and tools installed:</p>

<ul>
  <li><b><tt>libxml2</tt></b></li>
  <li><b><tt>zlib</tt></b></li>
  <li><b><tt>OpenSSL</tt></b></li>
  <li><b><tt>pkg-config</tt></b></li>
</ul>
And <em>optionally</em> also:
<ul>
  <li><b><a href="http://code.google.com/p/libproxy/">libproxy</a></b></li>
</ul>
<p>OpenConnect supports the use of HTTP and SOCKS proxies to connect to the
AnyConnect service, even without using libproxy. You may wish to use libproxy
if you want OpenConnect to automatically use the appropriate proxies for your
environment, without having to manually give it the <tt>--proxy</tt> argument
on the command line.</p>

<h2>Building OpenConnect</h2>

<p>If you checked the source code out from git rather from a release tarball
  then run this command first to prepare the build system:</p>
  <ul>
    <li><tt>./autogen.sh</tt></li>
  </ul>
  <p>Then to build it, run the following commands:</p>
  <ul>
    <li><tt>./configure</tt></li>
    <li><tt>make</tt></li>
    <li><tt>make install</tt> <i>(If you want to install it)</i></li>
  </ul>

<p>If compilation fails, please make sure you have a working compiler and the
<b>development</b> packages for all the required libraries mentioned above. If
it still doesn't build, please send the full output in a plain-text mail to the
<a href="mail.html">mailing list</a>.</p>

<h2>TUN/TAP driver</h2>

<p>Mac OS X users will also need to install the
<a href="http://tuntaposx.sourceforge.net/">Mac OS X tun/tap driver</a>, and Solaris/OpenIndiana users will need the <a href="http://www.whiteboard.ne.jp/~admin2/tuntap/">Solaris one</a>. Note that for IPv6 support, the Solaris tun/tap driver from 16th Nov 2009 or newer is required.</p>

	<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>

