<PAGE>
	<VAR match="VAR_ORIGIN" replace="" />
	<VAR match="VAR_CVSID" replace=""/>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_STARTED" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_BUILDING" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2-started.xml" />
	
	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

    	<h1>Building OpenConnect</h1>

<p>Unless you need to test the very latest version, you should not
need to build OpenConnect for yourself. Your operating system should
have a <a href="packages.html">prepackaged</a> version which you can
install; if it does not then file a bug or enhancement request asking for
one.</p>

<h2>Requirements</h2>
<p>To build OpenConnect from its source code, you will need the following
libraries and tools installed:</p>

<ul>
  <li><b><tt>libxml2</tt></b></li>
  <li><b><tt>zlib</tt></b></li>
  <li>Either <b><tt>OpenSSL</tt></b> or <b><tt>GnuTLS</tt></b></li>
  <li><b><tt>pkg-config</tt></b></li>
</ul>
And <em>optionally</em> also:
<ul>
  <li><b><tt><a href="http://code.google.com/p/libproxy/">libproxy</a></tt></b></li>
  <li><b><tt><a href="http://trousers.sourceforge.net/">trousers</a></tt></b> <i>(for TPM support if using GnuTLS)</i></li>
  <li><b><tt><a href="http://stoken.sourceforge.net/">libstoken</a></tt></b> <i>(for SecurID software token support)</i></li>
</ul>
<p>OpenConnect supports the use of HTTP and SOCKS proxies to connect to the
AnyConnect service, even without using libproxy. You may wish to use libproxy
if you want OpenConnect to automatically use the appropriate proxies for your
environment, without having to manually give it the <tt>--proxy</tt> argument
on the command line.</p>

<h2>Install vpnc-script</h2>
 <p>Since version 3.17, The <a href="vpnc-script.html">vpnc-script</a> that OpenConnect
 uses to configure the network is no longer optional, so it needs to be told at compile
 time where to find that script.</p>
 <p>The <tt>configure</tt> script will check whether <tt>/etc/vpnc/vpnc-script</tt>
 exists and can be executed, and will fail if not. If you don't already have
 a copy then you should install one. It might be in a separate <tt>vpnc-script</tt>
 package for your operating system, it might be part of their <tt>vpnc</tt> package,
 and there's one linked from from the <a href="vpnc-script.html">vpnc-script page</a>,
 if you need to download it manually. Install it as <tt>/etc/vpnc/vpnc-script</tt>.</p>

<p>If you do not want to use the standard location, you can configure OpenConnect to
 use a different location by default. When running the <tt>./configure</tt> script
 in the instructions below, you can append an argument such as <tt>--with-vpnc-script=<i>/where/I/put/vpnc-script</i></tt> to its command line. Note that the path you give will not be checked; the script doesn't have to be present when you <b>build</b> OpenConnect. But of course OpenConnect won't work very
well without it, so you'll still have to install it later.</p>


<h2>Building OpenConnect</h2>

<p>If you checked the source code out from git rather from a release tarball
  then run this command first to prepare the build system:</p>
  <ul>
    <li><tt>./autogen.sh</tt></li>
  </ul>
  <p>Then to build it, run the following commands:</p>
  <ul>
    <li><tt>./configure</tt></li>
    <li><tt>make</tt></li>
    <li><tt>make install</tt> <i>(If you want to install it)</i></li>
  </ul>

<p>Note that OpenConnect will attempt to use the OpenSSL library by default.
If you want it to use GnuTLS instead, then add <tt>--with-gnutls</tt> to the
<tt>./configure</tt> command above.</p>

<p>If compilation fails, please make sure you have a working compiler and the
<b>development</b> packages for all the required libraries mentioned above. If
it still doesn't build, please send the full output in a plain-text mail to the
<a href="mail.html">mailing list</a>.</p>

<h2>TUN/TAP driver</h2>

<p>Mac OS X users will also need to install the
<a href="http://tuntaposx.sourceforge.net/">Mac OS X tun/tap driver</a>, and Solaris/OpenIndiana users will need the <a href="http://www.whiteboard.ne.jp/~admin2/tuntap/">Solaris one</a>. Note that for IPv6 support, the Solaris tun/tap driver from 16th Nov 2009 or newer is required.</p>

	<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>

