<PAGE>
	<VAR match="VAR_ORIGIN" replace="" />
	<VAR match="VAR_CVSID" replace=""/>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_CONTRIBUTE" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	
	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

<h1>Contributing to OpenConnect</h1>

<a name="translation"/>
<h2>Translations</h2>

<p>The main thing needed at the present time is translations into
languages other than English. All contributions will be gratefully
received.</p>

<p>Translations for OpenConnect can be entered through <a
href="https://www.transifex.net/projects/p/openconnect/">Transifex</a>
or by editing one of the language files in the <tt><a
href="http://git.infradead.org/users/dwmw2/openconnect.git/tree/HEAD:/po">po/</a></tt>
directory and sending the resulting patch (or file) to the <a
href="mail.html">mailing list</a>.</p>

<p>If there are questions about the messages because the intent is not clear, or if the
messages could be improved to make translation easier or better, please also feel free to
ask or make suggestions on the mailing list.</p>



<h2>TODO</h2>

Other items on the TODO list include:

<ul>
  <li>Testing IPv6 on more platforms (only Linux, FreeBSD, Solaris are tested so far).</li>
  <li>Better support for running or emulating the '<a href="csd.html">Cisco Secure Desktop</a>' trojan.</li>
  <li>More platform support: Windows, Symbian, etc.</li>
  <li>GUI for OS X, perhaps based on <a href="http://code.google.com/p/tunnelblick/">Tunnelblick</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Submitting Patches</h2>

<p>Patches can be sent to the <a href="mail.html">mailing list</a> or directly to <a
href="mailto:dwmw2@infradead.org">the author</a> in private email. </p>
<p>When sending patches to be included in OpenConnect, please certify that your
patch meets the criteria below by including include a <i>sign-off</i>
line in your email which looks like this:
</p>
<tt>Signed-off-by: Random J Developer &amp;lt;random@developer.example.org&amp;gt;</tt>

<p>This confirms that you are permitted to submit the patch for inclusion in
 OpenConnect under the LGPLv2.1 licence. The full text of the certificate is as follows:

<ul><li><p><b>Developer's Certificate of Origin 1.1</b></p>

<p>By making a contribution to this project, I certify that:</p>
<ol>
  <li>The contribution was created in whole or in part by me and I
  have the right to submit it under the open source license
  indicated in the file; <b>or</b></li>
  <li>The contribution is based upon previous work that, to the best
  of my knowledge, is covered under an appropriate open source
  license and I have the right under that license to submit that
  work with modifications, whether created in whole or in part
  by me, under the same open source license (unless I am
  permitted to submit under a different license), as indicated
  in the file; <b>or</b></li>
  <li>The contribution was provided directly to me by some other
  person who certified <i>(1)</i>, <i>(2)</i> or <i>(3)</i> and I have not modified
  it.</li>
</ol><p>and also that:</p>
<ul><li>I understand and agree that this project and the contribution
are public and that a record of the contribution <i>(including all
personal information I submit with it, including my sign-off)</i> is
maintained indefinitely and may be redistributed consistent with
this project or the open source license(s) involved.
</li></ul>
</li></ul>
</p>

	<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
