<PAGE>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURES" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURE_CSD" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2-features.xml" />

	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

<h1>PAN GlobalProtect HIP</h1>

<p>The HIP ('Host Integrity Protection') mechanism is a security
scanner for the <a href="globalprotect.html">PAN GlobalProtect</a>
VPNs, in the same vein as <a href="csd.html">Cisco's CSD</a> and <a
href="juniper.html">Juniper's Host Checker (tncc.jar)</a>.</p>

<h2>How it works</h2>

<p>It is somewhat <i>less</i> intrusive than CSD or TNCC, because it
does not appear to work by downloading a trojan binary from the VPN
server. Instead, it runs a HIP report generator (built-in as part of
the official GlobalProtect VPN client software), which generates an
"HIP report" XML file.</p>

<p>HIP flow used in the official clients:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Client authenticates and fetches the tunnel configuration from the GlobalProtect gateway.</li>
  <li>Client runs HIP report generator and computes MD5 digest of report.</li>
  <li>Client checks whether a HIP report is required (<code>/ssl-vpn/hipreportcheck.esp</code>), including its MD5 digest and gateway-assigned IP address in the report.</li>
  <li>Gateway responds whether or not a HIP report is required (normally, it doesn't require a new one if a report with the same MD5 digest and same IP address have been submitted recently).</li>
  <li>Client uploads the complete HIP report to (<code>/ssl-vpn/hipreport.esp</code>).</li>
  <li>Server confirms acceptance of HIP report with a success message.</li>
</ol>

<p>If all goes well, the client should have the expected level of
access to resources on the network after these steps are
complete. However, two things can go wrong:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Many GlobalProtect servers report that they require HIP reports
  (#3 above), but don't actually enforce this requirement. (For this
  reason, OpenConnect does not currently fail if a HIP report is
  required but no HIP report script is provided.)</li>
  <li>Many GlobalProtect servers will claim that the HIP report was
  accepted successfully (#6 above) but silently fail to enable the
  expected network access, presumably because some aspect of the
  HIP report contents were not approved.</li>
</ul>

<h2>HIP support in openconnect</h2>

<p>OpenConnect supports HIP report generation and submission by passing the <code>--csd-wrapper=SCRIPT</code> argument with a shell script to generate a HIP report in the format expected by the
server. This shell script must output the HIP report to standard output and exit successfully (status code 0). The HIP script is called with the following command-line arguments:</p>

<pre>
   --cookie: a URL-encoded string, as output by openconnect
             --authenticate --protocol=gp, which includes parameters
             --from the /ssl-vpn/login.esp response

   --computer: local hostname, which can be overriden with
               --openconnect local-hostname=HOSTNAME

   --client-ip: IPv4 address allocated by the GlobalProtect VPN for
                this client (included in /ssl-vpn/getconfig.esp
                response)

   --md5: The md5 digest to encode into this HIP report. All that
          really matters is that the value in the HIP report
          submission should match the value in the HIP report check.
</pre>

<h2>Generating/spoofing a HIP report</h2>

<p>An example <code>hipreport.sh</code> script is included in the
openconnect distribution.</p>

<p>Depending on how picky your GlobalProtect
VPN is, it may be necessary to spoof or alter some of the parameters
of the HIP report to match the output of one of the official
clients. In order to capture the contents of the official Windows
client's HIP reports, enable the highest logging level for the "PanGPS
Service", and then sift through the giant <code>PanGPS.log</code> file
(which should be in the same directory as the executables, normally
<code>c:\Program Files\PaloAlto Networks\GlobalProtect</code>) to find
the HIP report submission.</p>

<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
