<PAGE>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURES" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURE_NONROOT" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2-features.xml" />

	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

<h1>Running as non-root user</h1>

<p>Under normal circumstances OpenConnect needs to be run as the root user.
If it cannot create the local <tt>tun</tt> network interface, you will see
an error such as:
<pre>  Failed to bind (TUNSETIFF) tun device: Operation not permitted</pre>
or in older versions, "<tt>TUNSETIFF failed: Operation not permitted</tt>".
The simple fix for this problem is, of course, to run OpenConnect as root.
</p>
<p>For security reasons, it is better if network-facing code can run
without root privileges — and there are a few options which allow OpenConnect
to run as an unprivileged user instead.</p>

<h2>Pre-configured <tt>tun</tt> device</h2>

<p>On Linux, it's possible to create its <tt>tun</tt> device in advance.
For example:</p>
<pre>
# ip tuntap add vpn0 mode tun user dwmw2
</pre>
<p>This creates a device <tt>vpn0</tt> which can be opened by user <tt>dwmw2</tt>
who can pass traffic to/from it without needing any elevated privileges. You
can now tell OpenConnect to use that device by adding "<tt>-i vpn0</tt>" to
its command-line arguments. Note that the <tt>/dev/net/tun</tt> device node
should be readable and writeable by everyone. <i>(Some distributions misconfigure
that, so if it isn't world-writeable then please file a bug against your
distribution.)</i></p>

<p>Of course, something does also need to <em>configure</em> the IP addresses
and routing. You could either add "<tt>-s /bin/true</tt>" to OpenConnect's
command line to stop it trying to run vpnc-script for itself, and manually
configure the network as root too. Or you could use
"<tt>-s 'sudo -E /etc/vpnc/vpnc-script'</tt>" so that OpenConnect itself
runs without elevated privileges but can still invoke <tt>vpnc-script</tt>
as root. Note the <tt>-E</tt> part which ensures the environment variables
with the configuration are actually passed through to <tt>vpnc-script</tt>.</p>

<p>NetworkManager usually has a dedicated unprivileged user <tt>nm-openconnect</tt>
and runs OpenConnect as that user, having pre-created the <tt>tun</tt> device for it.
OpenConnect then invokes a "vpnc-script" provided by NetworkManager which just
passes all the configuration back to NetworkManager over DBus.</p>

<h2>SOCKS / port-forwarding proxy</h2>

<p>An alternative option which doesn't require any root access
at all, is simply <em>not</em> to create the <tt>tun</tt> device and
modify the system's network configuration.  Instead, OpenConnect can
spawn a user-supplied program, passing all data traffic through a UNIX
socket to that program.</p>
<p>This option can be used in conjunction with a userspace TCP stack
such as <a href="http://savannah.nongnu.org/projects/lwip/">lwip</a>
to provide SOCKS access to the VPN, without requiring root privileges
at all.</p>
<p>SOCKS proxy implementions suitable for being used from OpenConnect
include:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/cernekee/ocproxy">ocproxy</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/russdill/tunsocks">tunsocks</a></li>
</ul>

<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
