<PAGE>
	<INCLUDE file="inc/header.tmpl" />

	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURES" replace="selected" />
	<VAR match="VAR_SEL_FEATURE_TPM" replace="selected" />
	<PARSE file="menu1.xml" />
	<PARSE file="menu2-features.xml" />

	<INCLUDE file="inc/content.tmpl" />

<h1>Trusted Platform Module (TPM) support</h1>

<p>OpenConnect supports the use of private keys secured or "wrapped"
by a TPM. Instead of being stored inside the trusted hardware as with
typical PKCS#11 keys, the key is encrypted by the TPM and handed back
to the user to be saved in a PEM file. Only the same TPM can decrypt
the file, and use the private key.</p>

<p>Use of TPM-wrapped keys is entirely transparent with GnuTLS. If built with
TPM support, OpenConnect will automatically use the TPM when presented with
an approprate PEM file with a TPM-wrapped key.</p>
<p>For OpenSSL, the appropriate TPM ENGINE must be installed correctly on the system,
and OpenConnect will load and use it automatically when appropriate.
</p>

<h2>TPM v1</h2>

<p>TPM v1 wrapped keys are supported with both OpenSSL and GnuTLS builds of OpenConnect.

These keys appear in the form of a PEM file marked with the tag:
<pre>-----BEGIN TSS KEY BLOB-----</pre>
These files can be created by the <tt>create_tpm_key</tt> tool which is
part of the
<a href="https://github.com/mgerstner/openssl_tpm_engine">OpenSSL
TPM ENGINE</a> or the <a href="https://www.gnutls.org/manual/html_node/tpmtool-Invocation.html">tpmtool</a> which is part of the GnuTLS distribution.</p>

<h2>TPM v2</h2>

<p>There are, unfortunately, two incompatible ENGINE implementations available for TPM v2 with OpenSSL.

For <a href="https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/jejb/openssl_tpm2_engine.git/">openssl_tpm2_engine</a> the PEM file has the tag:
<pre>-----BEGIN TSS2 KEY BLOB-----</pre>
The <a href="https://github.com/tpm2-software/tpm2-tss-engine">tpm2-tss-engine</a> uses a different PEM tag:
<pre>-----BEGIN TSS PRIVKEY BLOB v1-----</pre>

Both of these OpenSSL engines can be used by OpenConnect if they are installed.</p>

<p>GnuTLS support for TPM v2 has not yet been implemented but is being worked on.</p>

<INCLUDE file="inc/footer.tmpl" />
</PAGE>
